Vaishnavi Rama Shanmugam

MERN Engineer | Web3 Developer Chennai, India vaishnaviramashanmugam@gmail.com + (91) 96003 16393

#GitHub - /vaishu-shann

Full Stack Engineer, with 1+ years of experience. Seeking a position to utilise my abilities and skills in Engineering that offers professional growth while being resourceful and innovative to the Organisation. Always passionate to learn and find better solutions

Skills

Languages & Framework	 ReactJS (HTML5, CSS), Javascript (NodeJs) Python (Beginner) ExpressJS
Blockchain	 Metamask, TrustWallet, Coinbase Web3.JS Integrations: Magic.link, Transak
Design & UI	- Figma, Zeplin - Heurio
Databases & In-memory cache	SQL - MySQL NoSQL - MongoDB DynamoDB (Beginner) Cache - Redis
Code Versioning Tool	- Github - GitLab
Content Management Tools	- Prismic - WordPress, Wix

Professional Experience

Full-Stack Engineer, Coinfantasy

Jan 2022 - Present

- Joined as a Full Stack Engineer (ReactJS + NodeJS)
- Integrated Metamask, TrustWallet & Coinbase wallet for authentication in ReactJS
- Worked on FrontEnd development from scratch using ReactJS
- Using Web3.JS integrated smart-contracts
- Worked on magic.link & transak integrations

- Worked with team on server side API implementation
- Managed company blogs (wordpress) and official website (WIX)

Technologie used: Figma, Zeplin, Heurio, ReactJS, NodeJS, MySQL, Redis, Web3.js.,

Associate Software Engineer, Hash Dhronas

Apr 2021 - Dec 2021

- Joined as a Full Stack Engineer (ReactJS + NodeJS)
- Worked on various website development with the team
- Did Search Engine Optimization (SEO) for our web applications
- Hash Dhronas
 - Redesigned organisation's website using ReactJS
 - o Integrated Prismic CMS tool for dynamic content management
- Digifai
 - o An e-commerce web application developed for the garments industry
 - Worked on the UI development using Figma design
 - o Implemented REST APIs using ExpressJS & NodeJS and Integrated with UI
- Crank Masters
 - A system that provides automobile-related services & support
 - o Worked with team on UI development and did Primic integration

Technologie used: ReactJS, NodeJS, MySQL, Redis, Prismic.,

Full Stack Developer (Intern), New Tech Solutions

January 2021 - March 2021

- Joined as a Full Stack Developer (Intern)
- Learnt React & NodeJS and Code versioning tool Github
- Worked with team on creating new Pages & required APIs in NodeJS server
- Worked with MySQL & DynamoDB and implemented CRUD operations on serverside

Technologies used: ReactJS, NodeJS, MySQL, Redis, DynamoDB.,

Education

Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Science & Engineering

CGPA - 8.02

Institute - SSM Institute of Engineering and Technology, **Dindigul**